RG 079:001, Department of Environmental Protection: Central Office
Connecticut State Library
Department of Environmental Protection records
1944-2004
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection
203.25 cubic feet
Central Office includes: Commissioner; Staff Services; Bureau of Administration; Hearings; Tri-State Regional Planning Administration; Internal Affairs; General Counsel; Interagency files; Communications and Education; Affirmative Action; Human Resources.
RG079_001
Multiple
Historical Note
In 1971, the General Assembly created the Department of Environmental Protection to address "the profound impact on the life-sustaining natural environment" by "the growing population and expanding economy of the state." The new department consolidated powers and duties of a number of small state boards and parts of the Department of Agriculture and Natural Resources. These included the Park and Forest Commission, the Commission on Forests and Wild Life, the State Board of Fisheries and Game, the Water Resources Commission, the Boating Commission, the Shell-Fish Commission, Marine Resources Council, State Soil Conservation Advisory Committee, the State Board of Pesticide Control, the State Geological and Natural History Survey Commission and the Clean Air Commission.
Since its inception, the department has undergone numerous reorganizations as a result of evolving environmental issues and public policy mandating expansion of the agency's regulatory role. Restructuring the department to make it more "user-friendly" to business and to produce cost savings have also spurred reorganizations.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Included here are records from the Commissioner, 1957-2004; Staff Services, 1972-1985; Bureau of Administration, 1967-1981; Hearings, 1973-1984; Tri-State Regional Planning Administration, 1977-1978; Internal Affairs, 1973-1975; General Counsel, 1973-1974; Interagency files, 1973; Communications and Education, 1972-1998; Affirmative Action, 1977-1996; Human Resources, 1944-1974.
Arrangement
Series numbers have been assigned within RG 079 in its entirety and therefore the series described here are not numbered consecutively.
Series 1. Commissioner, 1954-2004,
Daniel W. Lufkin, 1971-1974, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 2 cubic feet.
Douglas M. Costle, 1973-1974, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 13 cubic feet.
Joseph N. Gill, 1957-1979, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 2 cubic feet.
Stanley J. Pac, 1973-1987
Subject Files, 1977-1987, Accession: 1988-018, 44 cubic feet.
Subject Files, 1973-1980, Accession: 1988-024 (part), 23 cubic feet.
Subject Files, 1974-1981, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 8 cubic feet.
Subject Files, 1977-1980, Accession: 1988-030, 3 cubic feet.
Leslie A. Carothers, 1987-1990
Chronological Files, 1987-1990, Accession: 1993-139, 2 cubic feet.
Speeches, 1987-1990, Accession: 1994-010 (part), 1 cubic foot.
Timothy R. E. Keeney, 1991-1994
Subject Files, 1991-1995, Accession: 1996-009, 1 cubic foot.
Correspondence, 1991-1994, Accession: 1995-038, 3 cubic feet.
Speeches, 1992-1993, Accession: 1995-039, 1 cubic foot.
Speeches, 1991, Accession: 1994-010 (part), 1 cubic foot.
Sidney J. Holbrook, 1995-1997
Correspondence and Subject Files, Accession: 2001-040, 5 cubic feet.
Speeches, 1995-1997, Accession: 1998-036 (part).
Arthur J. Rocque, Jr., 1998-2004
Log letters, 1998-2001, Accession: 2003-033 (part), 4 cubic feet.
Correspondence and Organizational Evaluation, 1998-2000, Accession: 2005-009, 9 cubic feet.
Rita Bowlby, Assistant to the Commissioner, 1973-1975, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 4 cubic feet.
Legislation Files, 1971-1991
Accession: 1993-140, 6 cubic feet.
Accession: 2003-033 (part), 10 cubic feet.
Miscellaneous Records, 1973-1997
Accession: 1999-026, 1989.
Accession: 1999-030, 1991-1994
Accession: 1999-035, 1973-1994
Accession: 1999-173, 1987-1997, .5 cubic feet.
Series 6. Staff Services, 1972-1985
Director George Russell, 1971-1985, Accession: 1988-022, 11 cubic feet.
Series 7. Bureau of Administration, 1967-1981
Assistant Commissioner Ralph Adkins Subject Files, 1967-1981, Accession: 1988-024 (part), 9 cubic feet.
Series 8. Hearings, 1973-1984, Accession: 1988-024 (part), 19 cubic feet.
Series 9. Tri-State Regional Planning Commission, 1977-1978, Accession: 1988-024 (part), 2 cubic feet.
Series 10. Internal Affairs, 1973-1975, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 4 cubic feet.
Series 12. Office of General Counsel, 1973-1974, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 1 cubic foot.
Series 13. Interagency Files, 1973, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 1 cubic foot.
Series 19. Office of Communications and Education, 1972-1998
Director. Subject Files, 1972-1998, Accession: 1998-035, 3 cubic feet.
Director. Subject Files, 1992-1993, Accession: 1998-036 (part), 1 cubic foot.
Director. Sound recordings, 1972-1996, Accession: 1998-039, 0.75 cubic feet.
Deputy Press Secretary, 1991, Accession: 1998-036 (part)
Series 20. Office of Affirmative Action. Affirmative Action Advisory Council administrative files, 1977-1996, Accession: 2001-017, 1 cubic foot.
Series 21. Human Resources, 1944-1974, Accession: 2007-044, 12 cubic feet.
Related Material
Additional Department of Environmental Protection records can be found in:
RG 079:004, Aerial photographs, see the.
RG 079:005, Air Waste and Water
RG 079:016, Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation
RG 079:018, Office of Indian Affairs
As well in these predecessor departments, boards, and commissions:
RG 079:003, Board of Fisheries and Game
RG 079:017, State Park and Forest Commission
RG 079:022, Forestry Department
RG 079:023, Water Resources Commission
RG 079:026, State Harbor Commissioners for New Haven Harbor
Other record groups:
RG 002:29, General Assembly Task Forces, Environment Committee Task Forces
RG 005, Office of the Governor contain files about the Department of Environmental Protection and its predecessors.
RG 015, Office of Policy and Management for records of grant programs transferred out of the Department of Agriculture.
RG 089, Department of Transportation contains the major statewide areil photographic surveys.
RG 098, Department of Agriculture
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection
Persons:
Lufkin, Daniel W; Costle, Douglas; Gill, Joseph N; Pac, Stanley J; Carothers, Leslie A; Keeney, Timothy R. E; Holbrook, Sidney J; Rocque, Jr., Arthur J
Subjects:
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection -- Records and correspondence; Environmental protection -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Minutes; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Commissioner, 1957-2004
  - Daniel W. Lufkin, 1971-1974; 1988-027 (part)
    - Alwin Construction Company (Box 19-1)
    - Connecticut Historic River Bill (Box 19-1)
    - Environmental Policy Act-Letter to Prete and Ciampi (Box 19-1)
    - Letter Sent to Oil Dealers, 1971 December (Box 19-1)
    - Press Policy (Box 19-1)
    - Comments-Coastal Zone Management Bill-Letter to Governor, 1973 February 28 (Box 19-1)
    - Cos Cob Power Plant (Penn Central) (Box 19-1)
    - Griswold-Mycelium Operation (Box 19-1)
    - Gypsy Moth-Letter to Oscar P. Stone (Box 19-1)
    - United Illuminating Company, rewires Mill and Quinnipiac Rivers, 1972 October 16 (Box 19-1)
    - United Illuminating Company, requires Quinnipiac and Littler Rivers, 1973 February 9 (Box 19-1)
    - Oyster Bay-Rye Bridge (Box 19-1)
    - Plan of Conservation-Development, 1972 November 27 (Box 19-1)
    - Harbor Pilots-Transfer of Responsibility Letter to Commissioner Wood, 1972 November 20 (Box 19-1)
    - Open Burning Directive, 1972 October 12 (Box 19-1)
    - Policy Letter-Trail Bikes on State Land (Box 19-1)
    - Letter to President Nixon urge approval of Conference Water Bill (Box 19-1)
    - Park River Project (Box 19-1)
    - Trumbull Lake Water Resources Project (Box 19-1)
    - Letter to William Greenough: When Should A University Take a Stand? (Box 19-1)
    - Stream Encroachment Line Statute (Box 19-1)
    - IBM, Letter to Frank T. Cary (Box 19-1)
    - I-291 Draft Environmental Impact Statement (Box 19-1)
    - New Haven Water Company (Box 19-1)
    - Testimony before PUC, New Haven Water Company Lands (Box 19-1)
    - PUC Hearing, docket no. 11165 (Box 19-1)
    - Environmental Quality Policy Act Testimony (Box 19-1)
    - Environmental Quality Policy Act-Letter to Prete and Ciampi (Box 19-1)
    - Enforcement Bill Commissioner’s Testimony (Box 19-1)
    - Enforcement Package (Box 19-1)
    - Connecticut Light and Power Co., Public Utilities Hearing (Box 19-1)
    - Statement by Commissioner to General Assembly Finance Committee, 1973 February 13 (Box 19-1)
    - Statement re: State Transportation Fund (Box 19-1)
    - Draft Environmental Impact Statements, I-84 (Box 19-1)
    - Policy Letter I-291 (Box 19-1)
    - Land Use/Transportation Study (Box 19-1)
    - PUC Hearings-Commissioner’s File (Box 19-1)
    - Solid Waste Testimony as presented by D. Lufkin, 1973 March 23 (Box 19-1)
    - US Army Engineers-Trumbull Dam (Box 19-1)
    - Press Policy (Box 19-1)
    - Governor’s Letter to IBM re: Land in Danbury-Ridgefield (Box 19-1)
    - Governor’s Executive Orders (Box 19-1)
    - Article by Allan Schoenhaus re: Solid Waste, 1973 March 18 (Box 19-1)
    - Solid Waste (Box 19-1)
    - Governor’s Task Force on Housing-Interim Report (Box 19-1)
    - Comments on Environment Impact Statement (Box 19-1)
    - Bankers Pollution Code (Box 19-1)
    - Comments on the Bristol Brass Article (Box 19-1)
    - Address to Connecticut Business Journal (Box 19-1)
    - Environmental Editorial by DWL (Box 19-1)
    - Report of Governor’s Commission on Tax Reform (Box 19-1)
    - Open Burning Revisited, 1972 November (Box 19-1)
    - Connecticut River Ecological Study (Box 19-1)
    - Dan W. Lufkin-Resignation (Box 19-1)
    - List of Speeches and Articles (Box 19-1)
    - The Business of Business is America, 1970 April 22 (Box 19-1)
    - Is the Corporation Dead?, 1970 September 22 (Box 19-1)
    - The Canary is Dead (Box 19-1)
    - Statement DWL-Acceptance of Appointment, 1971 September 17 (Box 19-1)
    - How can we improve the quality of life in the future? (Box 19-1)
    - Windsor Industrial Appreciation Day Celebration, 1971 December 9 (Box 19-1)
    - Connecticut Education Association, 1972 November 22 (Box 19-1)
    - Lincoln Birthday Remarks, 1972 February 12 (Box 19-1)
    - Anniversary Convention of National Association of Conservation Districts, 1972 February 16 (Box 19-1)
    - Joint Conference on the Environment Albertus Magnus College, 1972 February 23 (Box 19-1)
    - Connecticut Valley Chapter, Public Relations Society of America, 1972 March 14 (Box 19-1)
    - Mercy High School, Middletown, 1972 March 20 (Box 19-1)
    - Hearing Commission on Highway Beautification, 1972 April 17 (Box 19-1)
    - The Last Landscape, Connecticut Forest and Park Association, 1972 April 17 (Box 19-1)
    - Clean Air: A Challenge to Connecticut Industry, 1972 May 4 (Box 19-1)
    - 5th Congressional Kickoff, 1972 May 12 (Box 19-1)
    - Project Cheshire Cat, 1972 May 13 (Box 19-1)
    - Three Kinds of S.O.B., 1972 May 18 (Box 19-1)
    - NAACP Security Industry Tribute to Daniels and Bell, 1972 May 22 (Box 19-1)
    - Appointments in Tomorrow, 1972 May 26 (Box 19-1)
    - The Need for a Myth, 1972 June 1 (Box 19-1)
    - Big Decisions for Connecticut, 1972 June 19 (Box 19-1)
    - Six Tasks for a Modern Hercules, 1972 June 22 (Box 19-1)
    - New Haven Trap Rock, 1972 July 14 (Box 19-1)
    - Convocation Address: Hartford College for Women, 1972 September 8 (Box 19-1)
    - Partnership for Survival UAW, 1972 September 14 (Box 19-1)
    - The Power Struggle: A Question for Survival, 1972 October 18 (Box 19-1)
    - Overview of Environmental Needs, 1972 October 19 (Box 19-1)
    - Impact Zoning: A Plan for Connecticut, 1972 October 19 (Box 19-1)
    - What is an Environmentalist?, 1972 October 21 (Box 19-1)
    - Welcoming Address: Committee for the Future, 1972 December 6 (Box 19-1)
    - The Growing Edge, 1972 December 31 (Box 19-1)
    - The Buck Stops Here, 1973 January 9 (Box 19-1)
    - Environmental Protection in Connecticut: Problems and Challenger, 1973 January 11 (Box 19-1)
    - The Statehouse: Where the Action Is, 1973 January 13 (Box 19-1)
    - Breeding, 1973 January 25 (Box 19-1)
    - Playboy Revisited, 1973 February 2 (Box 19-1)
    - Profit with Honor, 1973 February 6 (Box 19-1)
    - Charging Times, 1973 February 16 (Box 19-1)
    - Energy—Crisis or Community?, 1973 March 22 (Box 19-1)
    - You and the Environment, 1973 April 17 (Box 19-1)
    - Army Corps of Engineers (Box 19-2)
    - Bicycle Trail Report (Box 19-2)
    - State Bond Commission (Box 19-2)
    - Connecticut Citizens Action Group (Box 19-2)
    - Connecticut Industrial Building Commission (Box 19-2)
    - Deerfield Foundation (Box 19-2)
    - Education (Box 19-2)
    - Environmental Defense Fund (Box 19-2)
    - Governor’s Budget Message, 1972 (Box 19-2)
    - Governor’s Washington Office Appointment of Renee Stuart (Box 19-2)
    - Information and Education Advisory Committee (Box 19-2)
    - Interview Questions (Box 19-2)
    - Herb Kramer-Commissioner’s Calendar (Box 19-2)
    - Miscellaneous-General (Box 19-2)
    - Legislative Liaison (Box 19-2)
    - New Haven Harbor Dredging (Box 19-2)
    - American Express Forms (Box 19-2)
    - New England River Basins Commission (Box 19-2)
    - You and The Environment (Box 19-2)
    - Grass on the Riverbank (Box 19-2)
    - A Time for Anger, A Time for Love (Box 19-2)
    - Appointment in Tomorrow (Box 19-2)
    - Wounded Knee Revisited, 1973 June 8 (Box 19-2)
    - Notes for Speeches to Republican Women’s (Box 19-2)
    - Governor’s Speech Soil Conservation Conference (Box 19-2)
    - New York Times Article, Exchange Students (Box 19-2)
    - My Dream for Connecticut, 1973 July (Box 19-2)
    - Foundation for Student Committee (Box 19-2)
    - Connecticut Association of Municipal Development Commissions (Box 19-2)
    - Politics of Pollution, 1972 March (Box 19-2)
    - A Modest Proposal (Box 19-2)
    - Environmental Editorial-DWL (Box 19-2)
    - Trash in Connecticut—Snow in Peking, 1972 May (Box 19-2)
    - The Work Ethic Revisited (Box 19-2)
    - Connecticut Water Company (Box 19-2)
    - New Haven Trap Rock Company-Wetlands (Box 19-2)
    - National Water Quality Standards Act of letters, 1971 (Box 19-2)
    - Public Acts (Box 19-2)
    - Public Hearing Notices from Commissioner (Box 19-2)
    - Public I&E (Box 19-2)
    - Public Works Department (Box 19-2)
    - Questions for Interview (Box 19-2)
    - Rattlesnake Sanctuary (Box 19-2)
    - Recycling-Returnable Containers (Box 19-2)
    - Car Registration (Box 19-2)
    - Resumes (Box 19-2)
    - Rickerby, Arthur Award (Box 19-2)
    - River Basin Commission (Box 19-2)
    - Sample letters (Box 19-2)
    - Scientific Institute for Public Information (Box 19-2)
    - State Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 19-2)
    - Scenic Highways (Box 19-2)
    - Solid Waste Area Meetings Information Package (Box 19-2)
    - Oil Spill-F.L. Hayes (Box 19-2)
    - Senate Agriculture Committee (Box 19-2)
    - Staff Board Meetings (Box 19-2)
    - Stevens, Gerald (Box 19-2)
    - Support Letters (Box 19-2)
    - Procedure for Transmittal Forms (Box 19-2)
    - Telegrams (Box 19-2)
    - Transportation Department (Box 19-2)
    - Travel (Box 19-2)
    - Travel Vouchers (Box 19-2)
    - UCONN School of Agriculture (Box 19-2)
    - Utility-Industry, Con-Ed (Box 19-2)
    - University of New Haven (Box 19-2)
    - University Research Institute of Connecticut (Box 19-2)
    - U.N. Conference-Stockholm, Sweden (Box 19-2)
    - Volunteers (Box 19-2)
    - Winward Oceanography Institute (Box 19-2)
    - Power Facility Evaluation Council (Box 19-2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19-2)
  - Douglas M. Costle, 1973-1974; 1988-027 (part)
    - Engagements kept, 1973 December - 1974 December (Box 18-1)
    - Engagements kept, 1973 September-November (Box 18-2)
    - Engagements Referred (Box 18-2)
    - Engagements Refused (Box 18-2)
    - Biographies (Box 18-3)
    - Agreements-CRRA (Box 18-3)
    - Radiation (Box 18-3)
    - Recap Island (Box 18-3)
    - Draft Report (Oil Refineries) (Box 18-3)
    - Refinery Task Force, 1974 August (Box 18-3)
    - Refinery Task Force, 1974 April-July (Box 18-3)
    - Refinery Task Force Public Hearing Tapes, 1974 December (Box 18-3)
    - Summary of Task Force Findings (Box 18-3)
    - Profiles: Supertankers I and II (Box 18-3)
    - Regulations (Box 18-3)
    - Regional Plan Association (Box 18-3)
    - Regional Plan Agencies (Box 18-3)
    - Reports to Governor (Box 18-3)
    - Resource Conservation and Development Project for Eastern Connecticut (Box 18-3)
    - Resources Recovery Authority Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 18-3)
    - Resources Recovery Authority-Minutes (Box 18-3)
    - Public Act 73-459, “An Act Establishing CRRA” (Box 18-3)
    - Resources Recovery Authority Draft Report to Legislature (Box 18-3)
    - CRRA (Miscellaneous) (Box 18-3)
    - Public Works Department (Box 18-4)
    - Public Utilities (Box 18-4)
    - Program Review Committee (Box 18-4)
    - Permits (Box 18-4)
    - PFEC (Box 18-4)
    - Post, Russell Lee, Jr. (State Representative) (Box 18-4)
    - Planning and Research (Box 18-4)
    - Pierpont and Company, Public Relations Counselor (Box 18-4)
    - Environment Committee (Box 18-4)
    - Phosphates (Box 18-4)
    - Petroleum Products Control Commission (Box 18-4)
    - Pesticides (Box 18-4)
    - Personnel and Administration, Edward H. Simpson, Commissioner (Box 18-4)
    - Personnel Status Report (Box 18-4)
    - Personnel (Box 18-4)
    - Parks (Miscellaneous) (Box 18-4)
    - Page, Stanley (Senator) (Box 18-4)
    - Pacer (Box 18-4)
    - Pac, Stanley (Mayor of New Britain) (Box 18-4)
    - P 17 (Box 18-4)
    - RYKAR Industrial Corp, Bridgeport (Box 18-4)
    - Rules and Regulations (Box 18-4)
    - Route 25, Trumbull (Box 18-4)
    - Route 7 (Box 18-4)
    - Resumes (Box 18-4)
    - Romanian Officials Study Tour (Box 18-4)
    - Carbone (Box 18-5)
    - Carlson, Adolf (Box 18-5)
    - Cashman, Peter (Box 18-5)
    - CEPA (Box 18-5)
    - Children and Youth Service (Box 18-5)
    - Civil Penalties (Box 18-5)
    - Clean Water Program (Box 18-5)
    - Clutrap (Box 18-5)
    - Coal Conversion Task Force (Box 18-5)
    - Coastal Zone Management (Box 18-5)
    - Collins, Francis J. (Box 18-5)
    - Commerce, Department of (Box 18-5)
    - Comptrollers correspondence (Box 18-5)
    - Comprehensive Grant (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut Business and Industry Association (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut Conference of Mayors and Municipalities (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut Park and Forest Association (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut River Diversion (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut River Dredging (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut River Transmission Line Crossing (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut River Gateway Commission (Box 18-5)
    - Connecticut Water Resources Planning Board (Box 18-5)
    - Conservation and Preservation (Box 18-5)
    - Conservation Commissions (Box 18-5)
    - Conservation and Development, Proposed Plan of (Box 18-5)
    - Conservation Foundation (Box 18-5)
    - Consultants (Box 18-5)
    - Contingency Plan-High Sulfur Fuel (Box 18-5)
    - Contracts (Box 18-5)
    - Council on Environmental Quality (Box 18-5)
    - CSEA (Box 18-5)
    - Dam Safety Program (Box 18-5)
    - Darney, Assistant Director (Box 18-5)
    - Data Processing (Box 18-5)
    - Deleo Brothers Construction (Box 18-5)
    - DEP Citizens’ Bulletin (Box 18-5)
    - DEPTAG (Box 18-5)
    - Directives (Box 18-5)
    - Governor’s Advisory Committee National Council on Environmental Quality (Box 18-6)
    - Letters to Governor (Box 18-6)
    - Governor’s Fiscal Speech (Box 18-6)
    - Code of Ethics (Box 18-6)
    - Equipment (Box 18-6)
    - Environmental Centers, Inc. (Box 18-6)
    - EPA, Boston, MA (Box 18-6)
    - EPA, Washington, DC (Box 18-6)
    - Energy (Box 18-6)
    - Energy Agency (Box 18-6)
    - Energy Conservation (Box 18-6)
    - Energy Policy (Box 18-6)
    - Environment Committee (Box 18-6)
    - Letters Referred from Governor (Box 18-6)
    - Governor’s State Information Bureau (Box 18-6)
    - Geological and Natural History Survey (Box 18-6)
    - German Marshall Fund (Box 18-6)
    - Letters to the Editor (Box 18-6)
    - Employees’ Suggestions Committee (Box 18-6)
    - Federal Water Pollution Control Act, 1972 (Box 18-6)
    - Flood Insurance-Federal (Box 18-6)
    - Flood and Shore Erosion Control Projects (Box 18-6)
    - Forestry (Box 18-6)
    - Farmington River Watershed Association (Box 18-6)
    - Federal Energy Office (Box 18-6)
    - Federal/State Relations, Office of Barry Budlong, Director (Box 18-6)
    - Grasso, Ella (Box 18-6)
    - Governor’s Community Forums (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Order Guidelines (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Order #16 (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Order #17 (533) (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Order #19 (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Order #21 (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Order #26 (Box 18-6)
    - Executive Orders (Box 18-6)
    - Governor’s “Interim” Task Force (Box 18-6)
    - Governor’s Press Releases (Box 18-6)
    - Bantam Lake (Box 18-7)
    - Bantam Lake Dredging (Algae and Weeds) (Box 18-7)
    - Bluff Point (Box 18-7)
    - Boating (Box 18-7)
    - Bureau of Outdoor Recreation (Box 18-7)
    - Nehantic State Forest (Box 18-7)
    - AD LIB (Box 18-7)
    - Ansonia Airport (Box 18-7)
    - Cable Television (Box 18-7)
    - Camping (Box 18-7)
    - Candlewood Lake (Box 18-7)
    - Coastal Zone Management (Box 18-7)
    - Connecticut Wildlife Conservation Bulletin (Box 18-7)
    - Connecticut Wildlife Federation (Box 18-7)
    - Conservation Commission (Box 18-7)
    - Cottrell Marsh (Box 18-7)
    - Coventry Lake (Box 18-7)
    - Dead Man’s Brook (Box 18-7)
    - Devil’s Hopyard State Park (Box 18-7)
    - East Hartford Golf Course (Box 18-7)
    - Farm Brook Watershed (Box 18-7)
    - Flood Control Projects, Still River, Danbury (Box 18-7)
    - Fish and Water Life (Box 18-7)
    - Flooding (Box 18-7)
    - Forestry (Box 18-7)
    - Great Meadows Race Track (Box 18-7)
    - Griswold Airport (Box 18-7)
    - Griswold Point (Box 18-7)
    - Harkness Memorial State Park (Box 18-7)
    - Highland Lake (Box 18-7)
    - Water Supply on Housatonic (Box 18-7)
    - Indian Well State Park (Box 18-7)
    - Inland Wetlands (Box 18-7)
    - Lake Forest Dam (Box 18-7)
    - Lake Kenoshia (Box 18-7)
    - Lake Lillinonah (Box 18-7)
    - Land Acquisition (Box 18-7)
    - Gift Land Acquisition (Box 18-7)
    - Land Trusts-New Caanan Land Conservation (Box 18-7)
    - Land Use (Box 18-7)
    - Land Use-Trialbikes (Box 18-7)
    - Mamonasco Lake (Box 18-7)
    - Marshes of New Jersey (Box 18-7)
    - Mashmoquet Brook State Park (Box 18-7)
    - Mill River (Box 18-7)
    - Morningside Beach, Milford (Box 18-7)
    - Nehantic State Forest (Box 18-7)
    - Norwalk River Watershed Project (Box 18-7)
    - Open Spaces (Box 18-7)
    - Osbournedale State Park (Box 18-7)
    - Parks and Recreation (Box 18-7)
    - Pequonnock River Dam (Box 18-7)
    - Pachaug State Forest (Box 18-7)
    - Pomperaug River (Box 18-7)
    - Roaring Brook (Box 18-7)
    - Rocky Neck State Park (Box 18-7)
    - P & C Sawmill (Box 18-7)
    - Shell Fish (Box 18-7)
    - Silver Sands State Park (Box 18-7)
    - Snowmobiles (Box 18-7)
    - Strickland Property, Middletown (Box 18-7)
    - Topsmead (Box 18-7)
    - Tracy Pond Dam, Waterbury (Box 18-7)
    - Trumbull Airport (Box 18-7)
    - Trumbull Lake (Box 18-7)
    - Valley Railroad (Box 18-7)
    - Vesta Vestra (Box 18-7)
    - Interagency Water Resources Planning Board (Box 18-7)
    - I-84 (Box 18-7)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 18-7)